Davis Knowles

Atlanta, GA 30310

Phone: 4704978248 | Email: dknowles52@gmail.com LinkedIn: linkedin.com/in/dknowles52/ | GitHub: github.com/davisknowles Portfolio: davisknowles.github.io/myportfolio/

Summary

Data Analyst with a background in business administration and entrepreneurship. Strong experience building data pipelines, analyzing data with Python, and visualizing strategic insights. Previous experience as a project leader and owning a business. Certified in Data Science and Analytics by Georgia Tech. Recognized as a hard worker who delivers projects on time and on budget.

Technical Skills

Tools: Excel, Python, Pandas, Matplotlib, SQL, AWS, Azure, Hadoop, PySpark, PostgreSQL, MongoDB, NoSQL, Scikit-Learn, Tableau, HTML, CSS, JavaScript, D3.js, REST API's, ETL, TensorFlow, Flask, Visual Studio Code, Git, Github, Jupyter Notebook, Google Colab

Projects

MinTrak: Supply Chain Commodity Tracker

github.com/davisknowles/MinTrak

- Used SQL, PostgreSQL, SQLAlchemy, and Flask to deploy an API for locating mining operations with Mapbox and enabling the team to access data for further analysis in Python and visualization in JavaScript.
- MinTrak's mission is to "accurately track the supply chain of strategic commodities from mine to market."

Mission to Mars: Web Scraping App

github.com/davisknowles/Mission-To-Mars

- Used BeautifulSoup, Pandas, and Selenium/Splinter to scrape several websites related to NASA's mission to mars then used MongoDB with Flask templating to build data pipeline to display with custom HTML page
- Mission to Mars curates NASA's latest Mars news, fact tables, and different hemisphere images

Employee Database: Data Engineering in SQL with Analysis in Python github.com/davisknowles/Employee-Database

- Created data pipeline using SQL and PostgreSQL. Built custom table schema for data extraction from CSV. Loaded SQL database into Pandas for analysis and visualization in Python.
- Employee Database allowed me to query and visualize two decades of employee data using a histogram of common salary ranges for employees

Experience

6G TIG Welder, Alta Refrigeration, Peachtree City, GA

June 2020 - April 2021

Welder on the Expert Piping team. Managed workflow to meet tight deadlines to ship on time. *Key Accomplishments:*

- Earned 3 certifications and promotion within the first 9 months of employment.
- Recognized by management for character and work ethic.

Project Lead, B10 Union, LLC, Atlanta, GA

August 2018 – June 2020

Led projects from beginning through installation, including the design and deployment of new systems and services.

- Deployed timesheet management platform from testing to entire staff within 5 days
- Monitored performance of manufacturing systems to minimize cost and maximize efficiency
- Helped define manufacturing strategy and processes
- Analyzed business requirements by partnering with key stakeholders across the organization to develop solutions for manufacturing needs

Owner, Knowles Welding Services, LLC, Atlanta, GA

January 2014 - August 2018

Welding and fabrication primarily serving the Hospitality industry in the Southeast.

Key Accomplishments:

- Engaged with award winning clients to define the scope of the project
- Planned timeline and resources needed for project
- Always delivered on time and met budget requirements

Education

Georgia Institute of Technology Data Science and Analytics Bootcamp, Atlanta, GA

Certificate, Data Science and Analytics

Georgia State University, J. Mack Robinson College of Business, Atlanta, GA

- Bachelor of Business Administration, Hospitality
- Inside Linebacker for GSU Football from 2009-2013
- President's List, Dean's List, Athletic Director's Honor Roll